earthshare.org 2018-06-10

# About: EarthShare’s Donor Privacy Policy

## DONATE ONLINE

Your gift can help protect our air, water, land and wildlife, and our health. Support for **EarthShare National** helps us continue our innovative partnerships and programs aimed at accelerating the pace of positive environmental change. 

EarthShare values and respects its donors’ right to privacy. It affirms that its fund-raising practices protect against unauthorized use of its contributor lists, and permits no general telephone solicitation of the public. 

EarthShare utilizes donors’ personal information such as names, mailing addresses and email addresses only for purposes of donor acknowledgement and/or when an individual voluntarily provides this information and opts to join our mailing list. EarthShare does not share donors’ personal or contact information with any third party organizations for purposes of solicitation. 

For purposes of individual donor acknowledgement, EarthShare releases donor names, contact information and donation amounts to those [**EarthShare member charities**](http://www.earthshare.org/who-we-support.html) that are designated by our donors, and only with the written consent of our donors. EarthShare strives to ensure that all donors who request acknowledgment receive appropriate acknowledgment in an orderly, timely and effective manner from the managing federation (either an EarthShare affiliate or chapter, or the national office) and the recipient member charity (for designated gifts). 

Visitors to the EarthShare Web site remain anonymous. EarthShare does not require visitors to register or provide personal information to view the site. There are instances when site visitors are asked for additional information in order to provide requested services. For example, information will be requested when making an [**online donation**](https://www.donationpay.org/earthshare/) to EarthShare so that the gift may be properly processed and receipted. EarthShare’s online donors choose the personal information that EarthShare receives and can opt to remain anonymous. All credit card transactions are conducted over a secure server. 

We use a number of web analytics products to optimize our website, including Google Analytics and Google Website Optimizer.  These tools do not require our site visitors to identify themselves, and they do not provide us any personally identifiable information about our visitors that is not supplied voluntarily. Our goal in using analytics is to understand what parts of our website you like and which parts need work.  We encourage you to accept cookies when surfing our website so we can do our job of providing you useful information as effectively as possible.

**EarthShare welcomes[comments and questions](mailto:info@earthshare.org) about this policy. Please contact [us via email](mailto:info@earthshare.org) or (800) 875.3863 if you wish to review or correct any personal information you've provided to us. We are committed to protecting our donors, and will make every reasonable effort to keep your information secure.

EarthShare's current financials, Conflict of Interest Policy, and [financial reports and 990](http://www.earthshare.org/financials-reports.html) are also available online for review.

**
